Betty Coe Cinquegrana Papers, 1960-2014 SC 0030
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Betty Coe Cinquegrana Papers,
1960-2014
Special Collections, James Madison University
Cinquegrana, Betty Coe
SC 0030
.98 Cubic Feet; 1 Hollinger box, 1 oversize box
This collection contains the papers of Betty Coe Cinquegrana, who attended Madison College from 1960-1964. Materials date from 1960-2014 and relate to her time as a student at Louisa County High School and Madison College, and life after college. Materials relating to the Betty Coe '64 and Paul J. Cinquegrana Scholarship, established in the mid-2000s, are also included.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated to James Madison University by Betty Coe Cinquegrana on July 15, 2014.
Bio/Historical Note
Betty Coe Cinquegrana, neé Betty Lee Coe, graduated from Louisa County High School in Mineral, Virginia in 1960. She was offered the M. Frieda Koontz Award that helped fund her education at Madison College from 1960-1964. As a divorcee raising two children, Betty's mother could only afford to give her daughter $100 towards tuition. The scholarships and financial assistance Coe received were vital to her academic success, and as such she wanted to give back to the College and help others with demonstrated financial need. To this end, she established the Betty Coe '64 and Paul J. Cinquegrana Scholarship, in honor of her and her husband, Paul. The scholarship is awarded to business students and future teachers. (See box 1, folder 36 titled "Making Gray Days Brighter," for additional background information about Betty Coe Cinquegrana and the scholarship in her name.) During her time at Madison College, Betty started out as a math major and later changed her major to business. She was also involved in many organizations such as Kappa Delta Pi, Phi Beta Lambda, Pi Omega Pi, and Zeta Tau Alpha.
Scope and Content
This collection contains materials related to Betty Coe Cinquegrana and her experiences at Louisa County High School and at Madison College from the years 1960-2014. Other materials relate to Class of 1964 reunions that were held in 1979 and 1989, as well as the scholarship named for Betty and her husband, the Betty Coe '64 and Paul J. Cinquegrana Scholarship. Membership cards, initiation awards, and pledge membership cards for Kappa Delta Pi, Phi Beta Lambda, Pi Omega Pi, and Zeta Tau Alpha are also included. There is also a school binder of Coe's that contains her notes for biology, algebra, English 102, and English 40 at Madison College. After graduation, Coe kept track of her fellow classmates and newspaper clippings of wedding announcements for her classmates are also included. Other materials include ephemera from her years at Madison and from her class reunions, including a class beanie and Madison College pennant.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in 4 series:
Series 1: Academic Life, 1960-1964
Series 2: Post-Madison College Life, 1964-2003
Series 3: Reunions of Class of '64 and Betty Coe '64 and Paul J. Cinquegrana Scholarship, 1964-2014
Series 4: Ephemera, ca. 1963-2014
All series are arranged chronologically.
Madison College -- History; Madison College -- Alumni and alumnae; Madison College -- Students; James Madison University -- Students -- History; Harrisonburg (Va.) -- History; James Madison University; Madison College; Students; Students -- Social life and customs; Universities and colleges -- Alumni and alumnae; Virginia -- Harrisonburg; Newspaper clippings; Diplomas; Notebooks; Report Cards; Maps; Membership cards; Certificates; Awards; Christmas cards; Photographs; Beanies; Pennants; Yearbooks; Medals; Printed Ephemera
- Series 1: Academic Life, 1960-1964
  Scope and Content
  This series includes documents from Coe's academic career at Louisa County High School and Madison College. Her 1960 high school diploma is included, as well as newspaper clippings announcing her graduation. There is also a letter from the Virginia Congress of Parents and Teachers to Coe that announced her as a recipient of the M. Frieda Koontz Award, which provided $300 towards her tuition at Madison College. An essay she wrote about graduating high school and the scholarships she won on senior night is included. The remaining items in the series relate to Betty's academic life at Madison College, from 1960-1964. Other materials include items related to scholarships she received (Bernice R. Varner) as well as Greek life and other organizations (Kappa Delta Pi, Pi Omega Pi, and Zeta Tau Alpha).
  - Louisa County High School Diploma, 1960 (Box:folder 1:1)
  - Louisa County High School Essay on Scholarships and Promissory Notes, 1960-1963 (Box:folder 1:2)
  - Louisa High School Memorabilia, 1960-1970 (Box:folder 1:3)
  - Betty's Notebook: Postcards, zipper pouch, and name card, ca. 1960 (Box:folder 1:4)
  - Betty's Notebook: Biology, ca. 1960 (Box:folder 1:5)
  - Betty's Notebook: Algebra, ca. 1960 (Box:folder 1:6)
  - Betty's Notebook: English, ca. 1960 (Box:folder 1:7)
  - Betty's Notebook: P.E. and Health, 1960 (Box:folder 1:8)
  - Betty's Notebook: Graphs, ca. 1960 (Box:folder 1:9)
  - Semester Grade Report and Certificate of Proficiency, 1961-1963 (Box:folder 1:10)
  - College Ring Order Sheet, 1962 (Box:folder 1:11)
  - Kappa Delta Pi, Phi Beta Lambda, and Pi Omega Pi Information, 1962 (Box:folder 1:12)
  - Pi Omega Pi, 1962-1964 (Box:folder 1:13)
  - Bernice R. Varner Scholarship Award, 1963 (Box:folder 1:14)
  - Kappa Delta Pi Constitution and By-Laws, ca. 1963 (Box:folder 1:15)
  - Kappa Delta Pi Certificate and Membership Card, 1963-1964 (Box:folder 1:16)
  - Madison College Student Handbook, 1963-1964 (Box:folder 1:17)
  - Zeta Tau Alpha Membership Card, Pledge Manual, and Poem, 1963-1964 (Box:folder 1:18)
  - Commencement Program and List of Graduation Events, 1964 (Box:folder 1:19)
  - Madison College Diploma and Photograph, 1964 (Box:folder 1:20)
  - Maps of James Madison University Campus, undated (Box:folder 1:21)
  - Newspaper Clippings on Coe's Accomplishments at Madison, undated (Box:folder 1:22)
  - Zeta Tau Alpha 1964 Composite, 1964 (Box:folder 1:23)
- Series 2: Post-Madison College Life, 1964-2003
  Materials included in this series are related to Betty's life post-Madison College. Included is her 1964 teaching contract with George Washington High School, located in Alexandria, Virginia. Other items include Betty's teacher evaluations for classes that she taught on steno-block and typing as well as a certificate from Future Business Leaders of America from the years 1982-1992. Additional materials include awards given to Betty in recognition of contributions to the Hospice Cup Organization from 1982-1992. The remainder of the series is comprised of newspaper clippings about fellow Madison classmates that graduated in 1964, such as wedding announcements.
  - Rough Draft of Job Resume for Spotsylvania High School, 1964 (Box:folder 1:24)
  - Teaching Contract for George Washington High School, Teaching Certificate, Teacher Evaluations, and Christmas Card, 1964-2003 (Box:folder 1:25)
  - Hospice: Philosophy of Caring Conference Certificate, 1982 (Box:folder 1:26)
  - Hospice Cup Information and Quicker Quicken Award Certificate, 1982-1992 (Box:folder 1:27)
  - Hospice Cup, Glen Oban Neighborhood Development Award, 1982 (Box:folder 1:28)
  - Newspaper Clippings of the Class of 1964, undated (Box:folder 1:29)
  - Synopsis of Resume, undated (Box:folder 1:30)
- Series 3: Reunions of Class of 1964 and the Betty Coe '64 and Paul J. Cinquegrana Scholarship, 1964-2014
  This series includes multiple items from reunions of the class of 1964, including a photograph of the women of the class of 1964 who attended the homecoming in 1979, along with a seating chart made by Jan Woods Marks (senior class president), stating the names of the women in the photograph. Other items include a September 1994 article from Montpelier magazine with pictures of the classes of 1959, 1964, 1969, and 1974, as well as short paragraphs explaining details about each person's life and an undated booklet for the reunion class of 1964. Other items contain information concerning the Betty Coe '64 and Paul J. Cinquegrana Scholarship and its recipients for the years 2008-2013, and letters of appreciation to the Cinquegranas from scholarship recipients. The concert announcements and the scholarship information were both originally located inside a James Madison University folder, but have been removed and placed in a new folder. The original folder is included.
  - Scholarship Information and recipients, and concert announcements, 1964-2014 (Box:folder 1:31)
  - Class of '64 Photograph at Homecoming, 1979 (Box:folder 1:32)
  - Octoberfest Related Materials, 1979-1994 (Box:folder 1:33)
  - Class Reunion of '64, 1989, undated (Box:folder 1:34)
  - Funeral Program for Paul Cinquegrana, 2007 (Box:folder 1:35)
  - "Making Gray Days Brighter" Article, 2014 (Box:folder 1:36)
- Series 4: Ephemera, ca. 1963-2014
  This series includes Betty's Madison College pennant and beanie. It also includes a Bluestone Society medal, her nametag for the 50th reunion for the class of 1964 held in 2014, a pin for the Bluestone Society, and lastly a pin for the President's Council. The President's Council pin is awarded for regular donations to James Madison University. Coe's annotated yearbooks from 1962 and 1963 were retained. The items in this series are all contained within one oversize box.
  - Madison Beanie, ca. 1963 (Box OV 1)
  - Madison Pennant, ca. 1963 (Box OV 1)
  - Bluestone Society Medal, ca. 2014 (Box OV 1)
  - Bluestone Society Pin and President Council Pin, ca. 2014 (Box OV 1)
  - Nametag for 50th Reunion, ca. 2014 (Box OV 1)
  - JMU gift bag, undated (Box OV 1)
  - Bluestone yearbook, 1962 (Box OV 1)
  - Bluestone yearbook, 1963 (Box OV 1)